(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-02T06:33:16.815153",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
収録の合間抜け出してゲーセン来ちゃった！
I snuck out between recordings and came to the arcade!
やばくない？やばくないこれ？
Isn't this crazy? Isn't this nuts?
ねねえじゃん！へ！
Hey, it's Nene-chan! Huh?
ねねえ、ねね、え？ねね？ねねちゃん！
Nene, hey, Nene, eh? Nene? Nene-chan!
あ、どーも、あ、こんにちは。
Ah, hello, ah, good afternoon.
100円ない！100円ない！100円ない！
I don't have 100 yen! I don't have 100 yen!
すいません、100円、あの、稼いでください。すいません、もう、ください。
Excuse me, please earn 100 yen for me. Please, just give it to me.
始まれ！どん！どん、どん、どん、どん、どん、どん！始まれ！始まれ！始まれ！
Start! Bam! Bam, bam, bam, bam, bam, bam! Start! Start! Start!
なに？ねねの何が始まってい言うんだ！
What? What does Nene's thing start?!
早く始まれ！どん、どん、どん、どん、どん、どん、早く始まれ！
Start already! Bam, bam, bam, bam, bam, bam, start already!
ねねリズム バースデーライブ！へようこそ！
Welcome to Nene Rhythm Birthday Live!
まずは遊びたい楽曲を選ぼう！
First, let's choose the song you want to play!
どの曲にしようかなあ？
Which song should I pick?
よし！この曲に決定！
Alright! Decided on this song!
全力女子革命！まずはライブ1発目！どの衣装で遊ぼうかなあ？
Full Throttle Girls Revolution! First live! Which outfit should I play with?
これかなあ？いや、こっち！いやいやこっち！いや、この衣装に決定えい！
This one? No, this one! No way, this one! No, decided on this outfit!
うわあ！何が起こってるんだ、何が起こってるんだあー！
Whoa! What is happening, what is happening?!
それでは聞いてください！全力女子革命！
Now then, please listen! Full Throttle Girls Revolution!
ぜんりょくじょしかくめい！
Full Throttle Girls Revolution!
いつもの私で今日も楽しく、好きなことをしよう
Today, like always, I'll happily do what I love.
張り切っちゃってさあ準備だ
Getting all fired up, now it's time to prep!
おはよう 少し眠たそうな私
Good morning, to slightly sleepy me,
「かわいい」を今日も纏って
Enveloped in "cute" again today,
全力が一番
Giving it my all is best!
周りの視線だとか
People's gazes and...
いつもの私で今日も楽しく
With my usual self, having fun today,
好きなことをしよう
doing what I love.
張り切っちゃってさあ準備だ
I'm all pumped up, time to get ready!
おはようなしそう眠れそうな私
Good morning, I look like I could sleep,
「かわいい」を今日も纏って
wearing "cute" again today,
全力一番
going all out at number one!
周りの視線だとか
People looking at me,
噂話だとか
or whispering rumors,
気にしない私は
I don't care at all,
私が好きだからいいんだもん
because I love myself, so it's fine!
だからキラキラ笑顔で
So with a sparkly smile,
オシャレなコーデにチェンジ!
change into a stylish outfit!
こんなに眩しいのは
Why is it so dazzling?
私だけのヒミツなの
It's a secret just for me.
キュンってしちゃうかもね
It might make your heart skip a beat,
可愛いからしょうがない
because I'm just too cute!
自信に溢れている
Overflowing with confidence,
私たちは
we are—
そうでなくちゃ
That's how it should be!
明日へのカードめくって
Flipping the card to tomorrow,
夢の中へバースイン!
birth-in into a dream!
いつだって自信満々のステージで
Always on a stage full of confidence,
今日は私たちがプリンセスなんだから
today we are the princesses!
たくさんの出会いと別れがあって
Through many meetings and partings,
大切な思い出だから
they are precious memories,
大丈夫って思える
so I know it's going to be okay.
伝えたくて希望の歌を
Wanting to convey a song of hope,
心は優しさで溢れて
my heart overflows with kindness.
踊りたくてドレスかざして
Wanting to dance and hold up my dress,
素敵な舞台に夢を見る
I dream on this wonderful stage.
だって1番のアイドル
Because I'm the number one idol,
いつか必ずなるんだ
I will definitely become it someday!
トビラを開けてほら
Open the door, look,
スターは目の前にある
the star is right in front of you.
ブザーが鳴り響く
The buzzer rings out,
そんな未来のため
for the sake of such a future,
マイクに歌声乗せて
putting my singing voice into the mic,
世界中に笑顔届け!
delivering smiles all over the world!
輝く星のように
Like a shining star,
最後はバズリウムチェンジ
finally, a Batulium Change!
かわいさのヒミツは私だけが知ってるの
The secret of cuteness is something only I know,
だから今だけ教えるよ
so I'll only tell you now.
ずっとトモダチだから
Because we'll always be friends,
この先どんな景色が待ち受けているんだろう
what kind of scenery awaits us ahead?
キラキラ笑顔で
With a sparkly smile,
オシャレなコーデにチェンジ!
change into a stylish outfit!
自信に溢れている
Overflowing with confidence,
私たちは
we are—
そうでなくちゃ
That's how it should be!
明日へのカードめくって
Flipping the card to tomorrow,
夢の中へバースイン!
birth-in into a dream!
トビラを開けてほら
Open the door, look,
スターは目の前にある
the star is right in front of you.
ブザーが鳴り響く
The buzzer rings out,
そんな未来のため
for the sake of such a future,
マイクに歌声乗せて
putting my singing voice into the mic,
世界中に笑顔届け!
delivering smiles all over the world!
いくぞ！
Let's go!
全力女子革命！全力で！
Zenryoku Joshi Kakumei! With all our might!
いくぞでも！
Let's go!
いくぞー！
みんな楽しんでいくぞー！
Everyone, let's have fun!
いっぱいスイカもよろしくねー！
Please take good care of the watermelon too!
輝く星のように
Like a shining star,
最後はバズリウムチェンジ
finally, a Batulium Change!
かわいさのヒミツは
The secret of cuteness
私だけが知ってるの
is something only I know,
だから今だけ教えるよ
so I'll only tell you now.
ずっとトモダチだから
Because we'll always be friends,
この先どんな景色が待ち受けているんだろう
what kind of scenery awaits us ahead?
キラキラ笑顔で
With a sparkly smile,
オシャレなコーデにチェンジ!
change into a stylish outfit!
こんなに眩しいのは
Why is it so dazzling?
私だけのヒミツなの
It's a secret just for me.
自信に溢れている
Overflowing with confidence,
私たちは
we are—
そうでなくちゃ
That's how it should be!
明日へのカードめくって
Flipping the card to tomorrow,
夢の中へバースイン!
birth-in into a dream!
明日へのカードめくって
Flipping the card to tomorrow,
夢の中へバースイン!
birth-in into a dream!
はーい、というわけで1曲目をお聞きいただきました！全力女子革命でした！
Hi there! So that was our first song, 'Zenryoku Joshi Kakumei!'
みなさん乗ってね、ホロライブ来てね、ネポラボのね、みんなの心の
Everyone get hyped, come to Hololive, and for Neporabo, everyone's emotional...
エナジードリンク、歌手、ももすずねねです！
energy drink, singer, Momosuzu Nene!
さあ今日はね、ねねリズムバースデーライブに来ていただきまして、誠にありがとうございます！
Now today, thank you so much for coming to the Nene Rhythm Birthday Live!
ねねの枠では初お披露目になるカラライズの衣装になります。
This will be the first time showing off the Colorise outfit in Nene's channel.
そして今日はハッシュタグももすずねねお誕生日ライブ2025、あ、ももすずねねお誕生日ライブ2025でたくさんツイートよろしくお願いします！
And today, please tweet a lot with the hashtag #MomosuzuNeneBirthdayLive2025!
はあ、あとね、MCの時間があと8秒あるので全力で水飲みます。
Ah, also, we have 8 seconds left for the MC, so I'm going to drink water with all my might.
はあ...、しゅしゅまちゅうお...、はい、というわけで
Hah... shushu machuu... はい, so anyway,
じゃんじゃんいかないとね、時間なくなっちゃいますので、次の曲行きたいと思います！
we gotta keep moving fast or we'll run out of time, so I'd like to move on to the next song!
かな、これかな、それかな
Is it this? Is it that?
いやいやいやいや、和服で決定でしょ！
No way, no way, kimono is definitely it!
ぴょ、ゆかた衣装！
Pyon! Yukata costume!
うわー、お着替えタイム、お着替えタイムー！
Whoa, changing time, changing time!
それでは聞いてください、放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Now then, please listen to "Housou Code ga Nanbo no Monjai!"
放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい
[Song: Housou Code ga Nanbo no Monjai!]
怖くなんか ないもん
There's nothing to be scared of,
だってあなたがいるから
because you're here with me.
もう覚悟は決めたよ
I've already made up my mind,
だから引き返したりしない
so I won't be turning back.
当たり障りのない世界そんなのクソくらえ
A completely inoffensive world? Bullshit to that!
だって本気の悪ふざけだからまばたきするな！
Because it's serious messing around, so don't blink!
及び腰の偉い人そんなのクソくらえ
Cowering important people? Bullshit to that!
だって本気の悪ふざけ剥れてくると危ない！
Because serious messing around gets dangerous when it peels off!
さあ、規制なんか振り払い、どこまでもいこう
Come on, shake off regulations and let's go anywhere,
……見たことのない 新しい世界へ
...to a brand-new world we've never seen before.
放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Who cares about broadcasting codes?!
ブレーキなんて必要ねえ！
We don't need any brakes!
放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Who cares about broadcasting codes?!
いつも心に白装束！
Always a white shroud in our hearts!
放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Who cares about broadcasting codes?!
始末書差し替え関係ねえ！
Swapping incident reports doesn't matter!
放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Who cares about broadcasting codes?!
後戻りはできない
There's no turning back,
なんぼのもんじゃい！
who cares?!
怖いものは……
Things that are scary...
だってあの人だから
...because it's that person,
もう覚悟は決めたよ
I've already made up my mind,
だから引き返したりしない
so I won't be turning back.
この世界
This world,
世界みんなで……
everyone together in the world...
だって本気の悪ふざけだからまばたきするな！
Because it's serious messing around, so don't blink!
及び腰の偉い人そんなのクソくらえ
Cowering important people? Bullshit to that!
だって本気の悪ふざけ剥れてくると危ない！
Because serious messing around gets dangerous when it peels off!
さあ、規制なんか振り払い、どこまでもいこう
Come on, shake off regulations and let's go anywhere,
……見たことのない 新しい世界へ
...to a brand-new world we've never seen before.
放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Who cares about broadcasting codes?!
談議で三十分！
Thirty minutes of discussion!
放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Who cares about broadcasting codes?!
アンテナ引いても関係ねえ！
Pulling the antenna doesn't matter!
放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい！
Who cares about broadcasting codes?!
なんて言ったらだめなの？
Why is it forbidden to say that?
どうせ放送しやしないなんぼのもんじゃい！
You won't broadcast it anyway, who cares?!
どうせ放送しやしない
You won't broadcast it anyway...
死ぬ時はみんな道連れネクロマンサー
When we die, we all go together as necromancers!
(死ぬ時はみんな道連れねネクロマンサー)
When I die, we're all going down together, Necromancer!
はーい、
Hi there!
というわけで、銀河のテルカドゥーちゃんの曲で、放送コードがなんぼのもんじゃい でしたー！
So that was Gingado Telcadu-chan's song, "How's That for Broadcasting Codes!"
この曲ね、ピーばっかりで逆にね、歌うのめちゃくちゃ難しい説があったんですけど、
This song had so many censorship "peeps" that I thought it would be super hard to sing,
絶対やりたい曲だったんで、今日みんなと一緒にあんすぺできて嬉しいです！
but I really wanted to do it, so I'm so happy to spend time with everyone today!
はい、ちょっと水飲みます。
Alright, I'm gonna drink some water.
ふうー、ちょっとね、最初のほう緊張して飛ばしすぎちゃって、息が続いておりませんー！
Phew... I was so nervous at the start and went too fast, I'm totally out of breath!
さあ、でもでもこっからはコラボファイトに行こうと思うので、ねえねえの息も整うのごうはつ…
Now, from here on, I thought we'd go for a collab fight, so Nene's breathing will also settle down...
というわけで、コラボパートいってみよう！
and with that, let's head into the collab part!
次はどうする？
What should we do next?
えー、迷っちゃうー！
Ugh, I'm getting lost for choice!
えー、どうしようかなあー！
Um, what should I doー!
よーし、この曲に決定！
Alright, decided on this song!
この曲はどの衣装で歌おうかなあ
What outfit should I sing this song in?
この衣装？ こっちの衣装もいいな。
This outfit? This other outfit is nice too.
うーん、この衣装に決定ー！
Hmm, decided on this outfit!
決めポーズで踊ろう
Let's dance with a striking pose.
巡り合う糸はきっと絡まるようになってる
The threads that meet will surely entangle.
リアルで感じる熱は
The warmth felt in reality
本物の誘惑
is a genuine temptation.
ドキドキ高鳴る鼓動
A thumping, pounding heartbeat
処理速度が追い付けない
that processing speed can't keep up with.
視野の先に映る君がいて
With you reflecting at the edge of my vision,
目に見えないメロディが弾く気がしたの
I felt an invisible melody playing.
ときめきはいつでも
Palpitations are always
変わらない夢の証でしょ
proof of an unchanging dream.
願い事集めてく
Gathering wishes,
カラフルに色づくストーリー
a story coloring up vibrantly.
それではパシャッと決めポーズ
Now then, snap a striking pose
リズムに合わせて
in time with the rhythm.
dance dance 踊ろうよ 踏み出して
Dance, dance, let's dance, step out,
天使のハートで 見せつけていく
showing off with an angel's heart!
これでもう妄想と同じ
Even with this, it's just like delusion.
最後はきゅっと締めポーズ
Finally, a tight concluding pose
リズムに合わせて 駆け抜けて
in time with the rhythm, running through,
天使のほほ笑み ドキドキさせて
making my heart race with an angel's smile.
これで妄想と同じだね
This is just like delusion too.
ああ だらだらしたら お昼までス―
Ah, if I laze around, it's a nap till noon,
寝不足ヘクトール お腹からグー
sleep-deprived, stomach growling.
集まってカフェラテ決めた
Gathered and decided on caffe latte,
あんず飴最後であげた
ended with candied apples.
縫ったり編んだり
Sewing and knitting,
案外のんびり 悪くないね 熱狂中
surprisingly laid-back, not bad, mid-enthusiasm.
ドキドキ重なる心
Hearts beating repeatedly,
真相まで追い付けない
can't catch up to the truth.
いたずらに微笑む君がいて
With you smiling mischievously,
駆け足で届けたいの
I want to reach you in a run.
魔法みたいにずっと
Like magic, forever,
トモダチはいつまでも
friends forever.
忘れない想いを広げてどこまでも続いてく
Spreading unforgettable feelings, continuing on anywhere.
同じ未来を見つめたい きっと夢の中で描いた この瞬間は君だけのめに
Wanting to look at the same future, surely portrayed in a dream, this moment is just for you.
キミの心と 私の心の距離を繋ぐ糸 準備はオッケー？
The string connecting your heart and my heart's distance, is preparation OK?
それではパシャッとあざとくポーズを合わせてダンスダンス踊ろうよ 輝いて
Then snap, striking a cute pose together, dance dance let's dance, shining!
天使の言葉で 魅せにしていく これで妄想と同じ 最後はきゅっと締めポーズ 心に問ねて dance dance 踊ろうよ 飛び込んで 天使のほほ笑み ドキドキさせて これで妄想と同じだね
Enchanting with angel's words, just like delusion with this, finally a tight concluding pose asking the heart, dance dance let's dance, diving in, making my heart race with an angel's smile, this is just like delusion too.
ランダム ブレイン！
Random Brain!
叫んじゃえ
Shout it out!
事件だ 毎日タイハン
Trouble every single day!
大成功のタネだ と
They say it's the seed of great success!
笑え…泣いちゃうな笑え！
Smile... Don't cry, just smile!
ぺこらっ たるんるん らっ た
Pekorandorunrarandoru
ぺこら ん どむ しちまいすたまえ
Pekorandom, got distracted again!
no no 脳の指令
No, no, brain's command—
無視か yes かうりゃー
Ignore or yes, or whatever!
no no 脳の指令
No, no, brain's command—
ランダムだ random！！
It's totally random!
no no 脳の指令
No, no, brain's command—
無視か yes かうりゃー
Ignore or yes, or whatever!
受取拒否れんぜ！
You can't refuse this!
一世一代 一念発起
One-in-a-million, resolve of a lifetime,
一心同体 同体？only one! NO.1!
as one body, body? Only one! No. 1!
おさいgirls and boys！！
Osai girls and boys!!
じゅんじょうかれんであれ
Be pure and demure,
うるわしきこうじょうしん
possessing a glorious ambition!
ぐっと胸にきざんで
Engrave it deep in your chest!
まえがみ スカートのたけ
Keep your bangs and skirt length
こうそくじゅんしゅしましょう
within school regulations!
ぴんとしてせいじつにして
Straighten your posture and poise!
せいじつに うけつぎたいのは
What we sincerely want to inherit
りりしいおしえを
is our dignified teaching!
げんざい かこ みらい なでしこの
Present, past, future,
まけないポリシー
the unyielding policy of a Nadeshiko!
don't be shy！！ほがらかに
Don't be shy!! Walk with pride,
ながされたりしないよ (by myself)
don't just drift along (by myself)!
ゆっくりと さかせましょう
Let's bloom slowly,
きよく ただしく
purely and correctly!
keep your pace！！いちばんのみかたは
Keep your pace!! Your number one
じぶん じしん
ally is yourself!
みんなもっともっと うつくしくあれ
Everyone, become more and more beautiful!
まっすぐに おすすめしましょう
Let's march straight ahead!
せいとてちょう の なかの
Living out the ideals written
しそうをじでゆくのです
in the student handbook!
なんてりそうてきなスタイル
Such an ideal style!
まなびはおんこちしん 心ざしをみがくべく
Learning is discovering the old
きょうも はりきらなくちゃ
to understand the new!
ゆうぎに、だけどきびしく
We've got to be enthusiastic today too!
一世一代 一念発起
One-in-a-million, resolve of a lifetime,
一心同体 同体？only one! NO.1!
as one body, body? Only one! No. 1!
おさいgirls and boys！！
Osai girls and boys!!
let's go, girls and boys!
here we go! NO.1! we are syd！！
Here we go! No. 1! We are SYD!!
don't be shy！！ほがらかに
Don't be shy!! Walk with pride,
ながされたりしないよ
don't just drift along!
ゆっくりと さかせましょう
Let's bloom slowly,
きよく ただしく
purely and correctly!
keep your pace！！いちばんのみかたは
Keep your pace!! Your number one
じぶん じしん
ally is yourself!
みんなもっともっと うつくしくあれ
Everyone, become more and more beautiful!
まっすぐに おすすめしましょう
Let's march straight ahead!
we love おさい. we are syd!
We love Osai. We are SYD!
おさい がく えん , oh!
Osai Gakuen, oh!
let's go girls and boys!
o・s・a・i・g・a・k・u・e・n!
O-s-a-i-g-a-k-u-e-n!
here we go! NO.1! we are syd！！
Here we go! No. 1! We are SYD!!
水ギのネネたちどうだった？
How were the swimsuit Nenes?
次はどんな曲でどんな衣装かなあ？
What song and what outfit will be next?
ここらへんで落ち着いた曲もいいかもね。
A calm song around here might be nice too.
オッケー！この曲に決定！
Okay! Decided on this song!
次はどの衣装で歌おうかなあ？
What outfit should I sing in next?
ちょっと落ち着いた感じがいいな。
A somewhat calm vibe would be nice.
この服...うーん、ちょっと違うかな、の服？
This outfit... hmm, maybe a bit different, that outfit?
いやいや、もっと落ち着いた感じの色み...うーん、あ！この衣装で決定ー！
No, no, a more calm colored vibe... hmm, ah! Decided on this outfit!
よろしくだよー！
Please look forward to it!
朝が怖くって起きられない
Morning is too scary to wake up to,
努力はそんなに向いてない
Effort isn't really my thing.
泣くことだけが得意になる、
In the gap of those days where
そんな日々の狭間で
only crying becomes my specialty,
ちょっとだけ疲れたんだって
saying I got just a little tired,
星の輝きがしんどいって
saying the starlight is exhausting,
言えないことだけ増えてって うつぶくように
things I can't say just keep increasing, bowing my head down.
明日が明日が来なければ
If tomorrow and tomorrow didn't come,
そしたらきっと楽になれる
then I'm sure I could feel at ease.
空っぽなのに心が痛んだんだ
Even though I'm empty, my heart hurts.
今日がどうにも寂しくってさ
Today is somehow so lonely,
眠れないままだけどさ
and even though I still can't sleep,
いつか幸せって思えるまで
until the day I can feel happy,
君は君のままでいてよ
please stay just the way you are.
もう強がらなくていいんだよ 過去の涙のひとつ
You don't have to act strong anymore. One of past tears,
それを柔らかく持って歩いていく
carrying that softly as I walk on,
それだけで今はいんだよ
just that is fine for right now.
いつか君が笑えるような 歌は歌えるのかな
Can I sing a song that will make you smile someday?
僕には何もないけど 歌を歌えるのなら
I have nothing, but if I can sing a song,
泣いちゃうくらいの優しさで
With a tenderness that makes me want to cry,
夜は温かくなるよ
the night will become warm.
君はさ君のままで笑って
You just smile the way you are.
今日がどうにも寂しくってさ
Today is somehow so lonely,
眠れないままだけどさ
and even though I still can't sleep,
いつか幸せって思えるまで
until the day I can feel happy,
君は君のままでいてよ
please stay just the way you are.
もう強がらなくていいんだよ
You don't have to act strong anymore.
過去の涙のひとつ
One of past tears,
それを柔らかく持って歩いていく
carrying that softly as I walk on,
それだけで今はいんだよ
just that is fine for right now.
制服のネネたち可愛かったよね！
The school uniform Nenes were so cute!
次はどの曲にしよう？
What song should we do next?
ゲストは次で最後みたい。
Looks like the guest will be next for the last one.
その前に1回ネネのソロを挟んどく？
Should we squeeze in Nene's solo once before that?
よーし！この曲に決定！
Alright! Decided on this song!
次はアイドル曲だから、アイドルっぽい衣装で歌いたいなー！
Since the next one is an idol song, I want to sing in an idol-like outfit!
どの衣装にしようかなあ？
Which outfit should I choose?
あ、これいいけど...
Ah, this is nice, but...
いやいやこっちでも...いやいやこの服！いやこっち！この衣装に...決定ー！
No, no, this one too... no, no, this outfit! No, this one! Decided... on this outfit!
着替えますよー！
I'm changing clothes!
いくぞー！みんな聞いてねー！
Let's go! Everyone listen up!
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Never, ever quit being an idol,
輝いてる君を見たい もうずっとずっとずっとステージにいて
I want to see you shining, please stay on stage forever and ever and ever.
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Never stop being an idol!
輝いてる君を見たい
I want to see you shining.
もうずーっとずーっとずーっとステージにいて
Stay on stage forever and ever and ever.
私がいもし人のとこ離れたなら
If I were to ever leave your side,
君はちょっと寂しくなるかな
would you feel a little lonely?
いじわる考える 好きな人がいるのか内緒にして
I have mischievous thoughts, keeping it secret if there's someone you like.
ねえ 神様は将来と 指輪をどこかに隠してね
Hey, God, hide your future and ring somewhere.
君の「好き」に合わせたんだ髪の色
I matched my hair color to your "likes."
私の中 君だけで 過剰摂取は中毒へ
You're all that's inside me, overdose leads to addiction.
責任とってね 大好きです
Take responsibility—I love you!
絶対アイドル辞めないで 優しい目も真面目顔も全て知ってる私が言う！
Never stop being an idol! Your gentle eyes and serious face—I know it all, so I'll say it!
絶対空で輝いて 星は街じゃ輝かないの 眩しい君が世界一だよ
Shine forever in the absolute sky! Stars don't shine in the city—you, so dazzling, are number one in the world!
君の夢は何ですか？教えて欲しい その夢がアイドルじゃなくても 覚悟はしてるから
What is your dream? I want you to tell me. Even if that dream isn't being an idol, I'm prepared for it.
星のない空 それが当たり前で 暗い道に目が慣れずに踏み出すのも怖かった
A sky without stars, that was just normal. My eyes weren't used to the dark road, and stepping out was scary.
そんな時やっと見えた光 「行くぞー！」
That's when I finally saw the light. "Let's go!"
絶対君は歌ってて ただのエゴとわかってても
You were always singing, even knowing it's just ego.
君はキラキラ衣装が似合う！
Sparkly outfits suit you!
絶対大きなステージで 一列でも前で感じたい 今日の歌い方 なんか好きだな
On an absolute big stage, I want to feel it even one row closer. Somehow I really like the way you sing today.
君の努力、私の愛 成り立つこの関係は 強くて脆いのかな
Your efforts, my love, this relationship we've built—is it strong or fragile?
星の幸せを願っただけなのに… でもね だって君はアイドルよ
Even though I only wished for your happiness... But you know, because you're an idol!
初めて目が合った日から 今日も明日も君ばかりだ
Ever since the day our eyes first met, today and tomorrow, it's all about you.
絶対アイドル辞めないで これは報われないおとぎ話 恋よりももっと好きだ 魔法どうこう解けないままで
Never stop being an idol! This is an unrequited fairy tale. I love you even more than romance, without the magic ever wearing off.
絶対アイドル辞めないで 優しい目も真面目顔も全て知ってる私が言う！
Never stop being an idol! Your gentle eyes and serious face—I know it all, so I'll say it!
絶対空で輝いて 星は街じゃ輝かないの 眩しい君が世界一だよ
Shine forever in the absolute sky! Stars don't shine in the city—you, so dazzling, are number one in the world!
君の夢は何ですか？教えて欲しい その夢がアイドルじゃなくても 覚悟はしてるから
What is your dream? I want you to tell me. Even if that dream isn't being an idol, I'm prepared for it.
星のない空 それが当たり前で 暗い道に目が慣れずに踏み出すのも怖かった
A sky without stars, that was just normal. My eyes weren't used to the dark road, and stepping out was scary.
絶対君は歌ってて ただのエゴとわかってても 君はキラキラ衣装が似合う！
You were always singing, even knowing it's just ego. Sparkly outfits suit you!
絶対大きなステージで 一列でも前で感じたい 今日の歌い方 なんか好きだな
On an absolute big stage, I want to feel it even one row closer. Somehow I really like the way you sing today.
君の努力、私の愛 成り立つこの関係は 強くて脆いのかな
Your efforts, my love, this relationship we've built—is it strong or fragile?
星の幸せを願っただけなのに… でもね だって君はアイドルよ
Even though I only wished for your happiness... But you know, because you're an idol!
初めて目が合った日から 今日も明日も君ばかりだ
Ever since the day our eyes first met, today and tomorrow, it's all about you.
絶対アイドル辞めないで これは報われないおとぎ話 恋よりももっと好きだ 魔法どうこう解けないままで
Never stop being an idol! This is an unrequited fairy tale. I love you even more than romance, without the magic ever wearing off.
これは報われないおとぎ話 恋よりももっと好きだ
This is an unrequited fairy tale, I love you even more than romance.
魔法どうこう解けないままで
Without the magic ever wearing off.
わあ！ねねの新衣装どうだった？
Whoa! How was Nene's new outfit?
最後のゲストの曲選んじゃう！
Now let's choose the guest's song!
よーし、この曲に決定！
Alright, decided on this song!
今日はおまるんがいないから、おまるんの曲をね、コラボで歌っていきたいと思います！
Since Omarun isn't here today, we're going to sing her song as a collab!
どの衣装で歌おうかなあ。
Which outfit should I wear to sing it?
はい、みんな見たいと思うので、新衣装に決定！選ばせなーい！
Yep, since everyone wants to see it, decided on the new outfit! Can't choose otherwise!
はい、変身します、変身します！はい、みて、かわいい！
Yep, transforming, transforming! Yep, look, so cute!
ご覧あれ！
Behold!
ハロハロエブリワン
Hello hello everyone!
まもなくオンステージ
Soon on stage.
ライツカメラアクションさあ
Lights, camera, action, now!
はじめようペルソナ
Let's begin, Persona!
ようこそパーティーナイト 誰かが語る
Welcome to the party night, someone speaks.
連日満員オーライ どうぞご自由に 待たせたショータイム
Packed every day, please make yourselves at home, the long-awaited showtime.
誰かが語る どうでもいいような 顔見せてよね
Someone speaks, showing some meaningless face.
クソ野郎共
You bastards!
hello! hello! everyone
まもなくon stage
Coming soon on stage
lie life 自己暗示
Lie, life, self-suggestion
さあ…始めようか。
Now... shall we begin?
「ようこそparty night」誰かが語る
"Welcome to party night," someone says
連日満員御礼 どうぞご馳走に
Day after day, sold out, please enjoy the feast
「待ってたshow time」誰かが語る
"We've been waiting for show time," someone says
どうでもいいような顔を見せてよね
Show me a face that looks like it doesn't matter
はぁ…偶像捏造炎上、並べた なら一攫千金？
Ah... Idol fabrication, controversies lined up—a quick fortune?
ふざけちゃいませんか？
Are you kidding me?
今辿り着いた憧れの 世界
The world of my dreams I've finally reached
ここはまるでペテン師の楽園 吐き気を飲み込む
This is just like a swindler's paradise, swallowing down my nausea
前略 幕が開けた そのオノマトペ
Dearly beloved, the curtain opened with that onomatopoeia
着飾る人形はピエロに口づけを
The dressed-up dolls give a kiss to the pierrot
本日大団円 脚本が笑う
Today's a grand finale, the script laughs
騙されてくれる貴方達と
With all of you who let yourselves be deceived
アタシ今ここで何をしてる？
What am I doing right here, right now?
耳をつんざく拍手喝采
Earsplitting applause and cheers
サルもおだてればヒトにもなれる
Even a monkey can become human if you flatter it
フォーカスされた日常 引き金を抱いて
Embracing the trigger of a focused daily life
心中するように
As if committing a double suicide
一回、二回、三回嘘を重ねて
Once, twice, three times, piling up lies
十回、千回、億回瞳を逸して
Ten times, a thousand times, looking away
あれ？なん だっけかな
Huh? What was it again?
アタシは誰？
Who am I?
もうウンザリした仮面舞踏会
I'm already sick of this masquerade ball
とりとめのないワルツでお迎え
Welcoming you with a rambling waltz
戮作の中に
Amidst flawed works
戯けてみて、嘲けてみてよ
Act the fool, mock me all you want
アタシの世界はぐるぐるクルクルぐるぐる廻ってく
My world spins round and round, dizzy and fast
前略 幕が開けた そのオノマトペ
Dearly beloved, the curtain opened with that onomatopoeia
群がる人形はダリアの花束を
The swarming dolls hold a bouquet of dahlias
選んでくれた服を着て踊りましょう
Let's put on the clothes chosen for us and dance
騙されてくれる貴方達と
With all of you who let yourselves be deceived
いいよもう これが好きだっただけだろ？
Fine, whatever, wasn't this all you ever liked?
振り落とせ ペルソナを
Shake off your persona
とっくに終わった 喜劇は悲劇と化してなお
The comedy that ended long ago turned into a tragedy
（今日も普通に楽しかったよ）
(Today was just normally fun, too)
さあ！刮目してくれてる
Now! Keep your eyes wide open
本当の僕はアタシじゃないから
Because the real me isn't who you see
（今日も普通に楽しかったよ）
(Today was just normally fun, too)
何故。
Why?
前略 幕が開けた そのオノマトペ
Dearly beloved, the curtain opened with that onomatopoeia
群がる人形はダリアの花束を
The swarming dolls hold a bouquet of dahlias
選んでくれた服を着て踊りましょう
Let's put on the clothes chosen for us and dance
騙されてくれる貴方達と
With all of you who let yourselves be deceived
いいよもう これが好きだっただけだろ？
Fine, whatever, wasn't this all you ever liked?
振り落とせ ペルソナを
Shake off your persona
とっくに終わった 喜劇は悲劇と化してなお
The comedy that ended long ago turned into a tragedy
さあ 刮目してくれよ 本物の僕はアタシじゃないから
Now, keep your eyes wide open, because the real me isn't who you see
前略 幕が閉じた そのオノマトペ
Dearly beloved, the curtain closed with that onomatopoeia
着せ替え人形と輪廻のアンコール
Dress-up dolls and the encore of reincarnation
本日大団円 脚本が笑う
Today's a grand finale, the script laughs
どうしようもないよな？！
There's nothing we can do, right?!
ああ、どこの誰でもいい
Ah, anyone anywhere is fine
「調子に乗るなよ」とたった一回言ってくれ
Just tell me once, "Don't get full of yourself"
そういやユングも散々言ってたな
Come to think of it, Jung said that a lot too
「もう後戻りは叶わない」と気付けばそこには一人で
"There's no turning back now," and realizing you're all alone there
ああ、どこの誰でもいい
Ah, anyone anywhere is fine
「調子に乗るなよ」とたった一回言ってくれ
Just tell me once, "Don't get full of yourself"
そういやユングも散々言ってたな
Come to think of it, Jung said that a lot too
「もう後戻りは叶わない」と
"There's no turning back now"
気付けばそこには一人で
Realizing you're all alone there
どうせフィクションの物語
It's just a fictional story anyway
この物語はフィクションです。
This story is a work of fiction.
ね、やっぱ、その前にこの衣装について触れなくていいの？
Wait, shouldn't we talk about this outfit first?
自己紹介もういいよね？自己紹介なんてもう我らはいらんでしょう？
We're already done with self-introductions, right? Do we even need them?
そう、新衣装だからさ。
That's right, since it's a new outfit.
もう、でも、これ、確かにこれは否定できないんだよな。
Though, yeah, you really can't deny that.
2人にはですね、この後のメインゲのアフターパーティーにて撮影会、カメラマンとして参加していただけます！
The two of them will participate in the after-party photo session afterward as cameramen!
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
え、どう、どう？ちょっとラミィとさ、なんかある感じなんじゃないの？
Wait, what? Doesn't it feel a bit like Lamy's vibe?
え、でもなんかちょっと妖精っぽいじゃん？妖精っぽいよ。
Wait, but it feels kind of fairy-like, right? Very fairy-like.
ちょっと背中、背中？背中？はーい！
And look at the back—the back? The back? Yes!
え、どう、どう？あ、緑担当と緑担当？緑担当？
Wait, what? Green and green? Green?
え、なんか緑っぽくない？でしょ？え、なんかエメラルドグリーン？
Wait, doesn't it look kind of green? Right? Emerald green?
でもありつつなんかちょっとぽいよね？ね？お靴も可愛いでしょう？
It has that subtle vibe, right? And the shoes are cute too!
え、可愛い！足、足、足！足映してあげて！え、でもそれメインでやったほうがいいんじゃない？
Cute! Feet, feet, feet! Show her feet! Wait, shouldn't you do that on the main stage?
見せられないよ！見せられない！やめて、やめて！見せないで！
I can't show you! Don't show it! Stop, stop! Don't look!
まだ見ないで！まだ見ないでください！
Don't look yet! Please don't look yet!
自分で出しちゃったんだよ。
She brought it out herself.
というわけで、獅白音とラミィはですね、この後ももう少しあの、出ていきたいと思いますので、
With that said, Botan and Lamy will be hanging around a bit longer after this,
一旦下がっていただいて。
so please step down for a moment.
ありがとうございました！ありがとうございました！楽しかった！また後でね！
Thank you very much! Thank you! That was fun! See you later!
はい、というわけで3人が来てね、ノーブルデイズもアゲアゲになったところで、次の曲いってみたいと思います！どうぞ！
So, with the three of us here and Noble Days getting all hyped up, I'd like to try the next song! Here we go!
ライブも後半戦！次はどの曲にしよう？
The live is entering the second half! What song should we pick next?
うーん、この曲にしようかな！
Hmm, should I go with this song?
よーし、この曲に決定！
Alright, decided on this song!
あれ？始まってる？これ始まってる？あれ、始まってるみたい！
Huh? Has it started? Is this starting? Oh, it seems like it's started!
あ、や、どうしよう、どうしよう？えっと、まちがえちゃった！
Ah, wait, what do I do? Um, I made a mistake!
どの衣装で歌おうかなー？
Which outfit should I sing in?
えっと、これでもいいし、これって、あの、あ、すみません！
Um, this is fine too, but this is—ah, excuse me!
これって、あの、あ、ちょっとみんな耳塞いでて！みんな耳塞いでて！
This is—ah, everyone, cover your ears! Everyone cover your ears!
スタッフさん、これって、あ、ちょっとあれですよね、チェンジな感じですよね？
Staff, this is, ah, sort of like a change vibe, right?
あ、待って、持ってこないで！持って持って持って！まだまだまだまだ！
Wait, don't bring them! Wait, wait, wait! Not yet, not yet!
え、曲がさ、曲が、う、まだまだ！やめてやめて！危ない危ない危ない！
Wait, the song—the song is, ugh, still not yet! Stop, stop! Dangerous, dangerous!
曲がね、ちょっとやり直そうか！やり直そうっか！もう1回ゲームの画面戻れ！戻れ戻れ！
The song, let's redo it! Let's redo it! Go back to the game screen once more! Go back!
次の曲、これじゃないのがいいな！
The next song, I hope it's not this one!
これじゃないかもな、から1回、曲選択画面に戻りたいなって！
It might not be this one, so I want to go back to the song selection screen!
戻れるかな？戻れるかな？あれ、あれ、あれ？
Can I go back? Can I go back? Huh, huh, huh?
じゃあ、ちょっと待ってだって、みんな！あ、やだ！ちょっと待ってる間に見られちゃうよ！
Everyone, wait a second! Ah, no! While I'm waiting, you're going to see it!
どうしよう、あ、見られちゃう！どうしよう、どうしようね？2人ともどうしよう！
What should I do? Ah, you'll see it! What should I do? What should both of you do?
助けて、2人ともー！
Help me, both of you!
はあ、はあ、ありがとう！ありがとう！ありがとう！
Haah, haah, thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
あ、やばい、見られてる、見られてる！あ、ちょっと、まだまだなんだけど、まちがえちゃった！
Ah, oh no, they're watching, they're watching! Ah, wait, it's not time yet, I made a mistake!
落ち着こう、水飲もう、水飲もう！水飲もう！今飲め、今飲め！
Calm down, let's drink water, drink water! Drink water! Drink it now!
獅白ボタンです！
It's Shishiro Botan!
ちょっとありがとう、2人ともマジ助かる！マジ助かる！もう1曲やろうかな？
Thanks a lot, you two are seriously a lifesaver! Seriously! Should we do another song?
ブルクラならできるぞ、今すぐ！ブルクラ、ブルクラ、撃たせてもらっていい？ブルクラやるか？
We can do Blue Cladius right now! Blue Cladius, can I fire Blue Cladius? Should we do Blue Cladius?
なんか、なんかと呼んで！
Call me something!
あ、わかった、わかった！えっと、みんな今から、あの、本当は、あのねえ、でテコスが歌いたい…
Ah, I get it! Um, everyone from now on, actually, um, Detekosu wants to sing...
たくて
wanted to...
でもちょっと、間違っちゃったみたいなので
But it seems I made a little mistake, so
生きてこそ歌いますー！
I'll sing "Ikite Koso"!
そのためになんだけど、ちょっと衣装、衣装ちょっとだして衣装。
For that reason, I want to change into my costume... outfit, please!
衣装は出るかな？
Will the outfit appear?
あ、でるでるでるでる！
Ah, it's appearing!
ちょっとねねね、「生きてこそ」は、森の民のねお話だからね、ムシキングは。
You see, "Ikite Koso" is a story about the forest people in Mushiking.
だからねねちょっと森の民になりたくて。
So Nene wanted to become one of the forest people.
はい、いま！はい、いまお願いします！
Yes, now! Please, right now!
キラキラキラキラキラキラ！
Sparkle sparkle sparkle...!
わあなんだ！あー！
Wow, what is this? Ah!
ちょっと何か変化が見えた！
Wait, I can see some change!
この衣装にけってーい！
I choose this outfit!
いえい！妖精さん衣装で…
Yay! In my fairy outfit...
聞いてください！生きてこそ！
please listen! "Ikite Koso"!
なんだとゆうんだ…
What are you saying...
なんだとゆうんだなんだとゆうんだー！
What is this supposed to mean?
妖精さん衣装で、聞いてください！生きてこそ！
Please listen in my fairy outfit! "Ikite Koso"!
ママ私が 生まれた日の 空はどんな色
Mama, what color was the sky on the day I was born?
パパ私が 生まれた日の 気持ちはどうだった?
Papa, how did you feel on the day I was born?
あれから言葉を覚えて 私なりの 愛も甘え方も 身体にしみこんだ
Ever since then, learning words, my own way of loving and leaning on others soaked into my body.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ 今ここから始まる
To live, to live, it starts right here and now.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ 広がってまたつながる
To live, to live, spreading out and connecting once again.
ママ私を 初めて抱く 気持ちはどうだった?
Mama, how did you feel when you held me for the very first time?
パパ私が 生まれた日は 嬉しかった?
Papa, were you happy on the day I was born?
あれからキセキを重ねて 私なりの 愛も出会いも 育てていきたい
Accumulating miracles since then... I want to nurture my own love and encounters.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ 無限に羽ばたいていく夢
To live, to live, dreams taking flight infinitely.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ その根は 深く 太く 強く
To live, to live, their roots growing deep, thick, and strong.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ 今ここから始まる
To live, to live, it starts right here and now.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ 広がってまたつながる
To live, to live, spreading out and connecting once again.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ 無限に羽ばたいていく夢
To live, to live, dreams taking flight infinitely.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ その根は 深く 太く 強く
To live, to live, their roots growing deep, thick, and strong.
その根は 深く 太く 強く
Their roots growing deep, thick, and strong.
yeah
羽ばたいて 生きてこそ Ah...
Taking flight, to live... Ah...
はい、というわけで
Alright, with that said...
立て続けの感想、というわけで
That was fun reviewing everything!
生きてこそでしたー！
Live to Live just ended!
そして見てください、これ！妖精バージョンでいまーす。
And look at this, Fairy Version!
ちょっとね、あんまり詳しい変化は、や、教えられないかわあんだけど
I'm not good at explaining detailed changes, but...
まず、足が素足になっちゃいました。森の妖精っぽいでしょう？
First, her feet are barefoot now! Kind of fairy-like, right?
そして、ズボンだったのがスカートに変わっちゃいました。
And her shorts turned into a skirt!
そして、羽が！羽が生えました！イエーイ！
And wings! Wings appeared! Yay!
詳しくないけど、後でじっくり見てください！
Be sure to look closely at the details later!
さあちょっとね遅れ取っちゃったので、どんどん行きたいと思います！次の曲行ってみよー！
Sorry I'm running late, let's move on to the next song!
ライブも後半戦！
The live is in its second half!
次はどの曲にしよう？
Which song should we do next?
うーん、この曲にしようかな。
Hmm, should I pick this song?
よーし！この曲に決定！
Alright, I'm choosing this song!
この衣装はどの衣装で遊ぼっかなというわけで
Now, what outfit should we wear for this?
ここからは視聴者参加型！ねねのね、次「未来形Answer」を歌う服装はみんなにアンケートで決めていただきたいと思います！
From here on, it'll be viewer-participatory! We'll decide Nene's next outfit, "Mirai-gata Answer," through a poll with everyone!
コメントでアンケート取るので参加してください！
We'll do a poll in chat, so please join!
選択肢はさっきの桃鈴ねねのね、新衣装カジュアル衣装、羽生えてない方ですね。
The choices are: first, Momosuzu Nene's normal casual outfit (the one without wings)...
そして、ねねのいま着てるお洋服、妖精バージョンのねね。
Second, Nene's current outfit, the fairy version...
そして、この配信で初お披露目のカラーライズ衣装！
And third, the color-rise outfit that debuted on this stream!
次の曲はね、ふわっと可愛い力強めの曲ですね。この曲にあったお洋服をみんなで選んでください！
The next song is a fluffy, cute, high-energy one, so please pick the outfit that fits best!
それではアンケートスタート！
Alright, let's start the poll!
お待ちますお待ちます、水も飲みます。
Wait for it, wait for it, drinking some water.
じゃあ走った！足走りすぎて足ドバドバになっちゃったみんな。
Oh, wait, everyone's running too much, sweating like crazy!
どれにしてくれるのかなみんな。ドリドリドリドリ、今のところは
Which one will you pick for me, everyone? Dori, dori, dori, dori... what about right now?
おっ！あれどうしようどうしようみんなの姉着せてくれるの？
Oh! Wait, what? Which sister is wearing it?
いい勝負、いい勝負だみんな！
It's a close match, it's a close match, everyone!
どうなっちゃうのかなー。
Where is this going?
何かしら？どれにしてくれるのみんな？
What? Which one will you choose, everyone?
あ、迷う？カラーライズも見たい？え、だよねだよね。
Ah, you want to see Color-Rise too? Yeah, right, right.
あとからね、あの、この衣装はねペンギンでいっぱい見れちゃうからね。カラーライズもいいなー。
Later on, you can see this outfit with the penguin too, so Color-Rise is good too...
でもせっかくなら新衣装ゆっくり見たい気もするでしょ？どれがいいかなー。
But since we have the chance, we might want to see the new outfit slowly too, which one is better?
あともう少しまだかな？あと何分ぐらい？
A little more, still time left, maybe a few more minutes?
あと30秒であの締め切りたいと思いますので、みなさん選んでねー！
We'll close the poll in 30 seconds, so everyone, please vote!
いま参加してきてくれた人、
Everyone who's voting now,
次のねねが歌う服をいまみんなにアンケートで決めてもらっております！
Nene's already decided the outfit for the next song through your votes!
もうすぐで投票終わっちゃうので、まだ推してない人はポチー！
The voting is almost over, so if you haven't voted yet, click!
どっちかな？どれかな？どっちかな？どれかな？
Which one? Which one? Which one? Which one?
終了ー！
Ending!
結果は、おっすごい良い勝負なんですけど、カラーライズ衣装で決定ー！
The result is... Oh, what a close match! But it's the Color-Rise outfit, decision!
はっ！
Tada!
それでは歌っていきましょう！未来形Answer！
Then let's sing it, "Mirai-gata Answer"!
追いかけない 追いかけたいのに
I can't catch up with you, even though I want to
突然物語
It's suddenly our story
ギビナンサー
Give me an answer
わからないよAnswer
I don't understand this answer
未来形Answer
Mirai-gata Answer
追いかけられない 追いかけたいのに
I can't catch up with you, even though I want to
突然、物語 give me an answer
It's suddenly our story, give me an answer
わからないよ answer
I don't understand this answer
お菓子みたいに「好き」も
Wouldn't it be nice if, like candy, love too
レシピ通りに行けばいいのに
Could follow a recipe
メレンゲみたいに距離も
Like meringue, the distance too
時間次第で変われたらいいのに
Could change depending on time
冷静さと熱血が幼馴染なんだ
Coolness and passion are old friends
一生手も繋げないままかな
I wonder if we'll never hold hands
やだよ
No way!
追いつけない 追いつきたいのに
I can't catch up with you, even though I want to
突然、物語 give me an answer
It's suddenly our story, give me an answer
不器用でぎこちないほど
It's so clumsy and awkward
愛しくはじまるの？ give me an answer
Is it starting to become precious? Give me an answer
未来形の answer
A future-tense answer
アイシングで描く未来図に降る
Dragees rain down on the future map
アラザンの雨
Drawn in icing...
オレンジピールが苦い
Orange peel is bitter
ビタースィートって奥が深いな
Calling it 'bittersweet' is profound
未来形の answer
A future-tense answer
冗談じゃない からかってない
This isn't a joke, I'm not teasing
ちゃんときみがいいの
I want you, just the way you are
見当違いやめて わたしを見て
Stop looking elsewhere, look at me
早く!!
Quickly!
何でもない 何でもないけど
It's nothing, no particular reason, but
明日は晴れるかな
I wonder if it will be sunny tomorrow?
give me an answer
優しいね それ苦しいの
You're kind, which makes this so painful
次いつ逢えるかな
I wonder when we'll see each other next?
give me an answer
未完成の answer
An incomplete answer
ため息の糖量
A sigh with a bit of sugar
「ありがとう」って言ったあの日から
You said, "Thank you", and ever since that day
微熱がずっと下がらないの…
I've been overcome with a fever...
追いかけられない 追いかけたいのに
I can't catch up with you, even though I want to
わたしの物語 give me an answer
It's my story, give me an answer
不器用でぎこちないほど
It's so clumsy and awkward
愛しくはじまるの？ give me an answer
Is it starting to become precious? Give me an answer
未来形の answer
A future-tense answer
わからないよ answer
I don't understand this answer
わかりたいよ answer
I want to understand this answer
ため息の糖量
A sigh with a bit of sugar
「ありがとう」って言ったあの日から
You said, "Thank you", and ever since that day
微熱がずっと下がらないの…
I've been overcome with a fever...
追いかけられない 追いかけたいのに
I can't catch up with you, even though I want to
わたしの物語 give me an answer
It's my story, give me an answer
不器用でぎこちないほど
It's so clumsy and awkward
愛しくはじまるの？ give me an answer
Is it starting to become precious? Give me an answer
未来形の answer
A future-tense answer
わからないよ answer
I don't understand this answer
わかりたいよ answer
I want to understand this answer
未来形の answer
A future-tense answer
わからないよ answer
I don't understand this answer
わかりたいよ answer
I want to understand this answer
はーい！というわけで未来形Answerをお聴きいただきました！みんな選んでくれてありがとねー！
Hi there! So that was "Miraikei Answer"! Thank you everyone for picking it!
オレンジのアクセントね、めっちゃこの衣装に映えてかわいいと思っております！イエーイ！
The orange accents really pop with this outfit and I think it's super cute! Yay!
そして、今からなんですけれども、みんなにお知らせがあります！というわけで、ししらみも1回来て！ねえ！
And now, I have an announcement for everyone! So, Shishirami, come on out here for a sec! Hey!
なんじゃなんじゃー！
What is it, what is it?!
ちょっとさっきマジでありがとう！
Seriously, thank you so much earlier!
ブルクラならいつでもできるから！ねえやるか？今から？
We can do the Blue Crystal anytime! Want to do it right now?
マジであせっ…ブルクラだけ用意しとこうぜ今から！ちょっと！いす持ってきて！いす用意してくれ！
Wait, seriously... let's prep the Blue Crystal right now! Hey, bring a chair! Get a chair ready!
なになにですか？あ、おしらせ！おしらせね！はい！
What's going on? Oh, the announcement! Right, the announcement!
そうそうそうね、誕生日記念グッズが出まーす！やったー！
That's right, my birthday commemorative merch is out! Yay!
どんなの？どんなの？ 全体はこ・ち・ら！
What's it like? What's it like? Here it is overall!
桃鈴ねね誕生日記念2025
[Momosuzu Nene Birthday Celebration 2025 - Full Set]
ももすずねね誕生日記念2025！かわいい！
Momosuzu Nene Birthday Celebration 2025! So cute!
1章のなんとグッズが初めて出ます！おー！いいね！
For the first time, Chapter 1 goods are coming out! Oh, nice!
1つずつ見ていきましょう！1つ目はこ・ち・ら！どーん！
Let's check them out one by one! First up is... bam!
あ、ちょっと目に汗が動いてる…
Ah, I've got sweat in my eyes...
ねねちの紹介してくんない？そうね！はいはいはい！
Won't you introduce Nene's? That's right! Yes, yes, yes!
このキャンバスアートはですね、ねねちの、新！あれですね、新3D衣装の、はい、
This canvas art features Nene's, new! That's right, her new 3D outfit—
かわいい森の妖精チックな
with a cute, forest fairy-like vibe.
キャンバスアート！マジでかわいいからね！ねねちの衣装めっっちゃかわいい！
Canvas art! It's seriously so cute! Nene's outfit is suuuper cute!
え、なんかね、でも聞いた話によると、あたし以外みんな出してるらしいの、ねぽらぼで。
Wait, but I heard that everyone except me is putting one out in Nelabo?
ねぽらぼではね！ねぽらぼね！そう！ねぽらぼではね！
In Nelabo? Nelabo? That's right! In Nelabo!
ねぽらぼでねね以外全員キャンバスアート出してると思ったらの関係のとこ。
I thought everyone in Nelabo besides Nene was putting out canvas art, but...
ししろんもまだ出てなかったから、そうね、はい。
Shishiron hadn't come out yet either, so that's right, yes.
はい、そして次はこちら！ねっこ証明書！
Right, and next is this! The Neko Certificate!
おおー！なんだそれ、なんだそれ！
Ooh! What is that, what is that!
これは昔ねねがねねプロの証明書っていうのを作ったときに、
This is when Nene made a certificate for Nene Pro a long time ago,
まだそのときねねのね、ねっこじゃなかったみんなが、「僕も欲しい！僕も欲しい！」って言ってくれたので、
and back then, everyone who wasn't a 'Neko' yet said, 'I want one too! I want one too!'
2回目で、ねぽらぼの、あ、じゃなくてねぽらぼじゃない、巻き込んじゃった。
so for the second time, in Nelabo, oh wait, not Nelabo, I dragged them into it.
巻き込んじゃった。いや、でもね、走りすぎてる。落ち着いて！
I dragged them into it. Well, but you know, you're rushing too much. Calm down!
落ち着いて！大丈夫だよ、大丈夫だぞ！
Calm down! It's alright, it'll be fine!
ねっこ証明書が出ます！イエーイ！
The Neko Certificate is coming out! Yay!
グレーになってるところがあると思うんだけど、
There are parts that are grey, right?
そこはみんながオリジナルのねっこを作りがえて、ここに写真貼ったり名前書いたり色塗ったりしてほしいなっていう思いを込めて。
That's made with the wish that everyone will create their own original Neko, paste a photo, write their name, or color it.
で、ねねの保存方法って瓶の中なんだよね。液体に入れて。
And Nene's preservation method is in a jar. Put in liquid.
あれ？液体に入れてるんだね。あれやってやってれば一生元気でいられ
Huh? You put it in liquid? If you keep doing that, you can stay energetic forever—
あ、確かにね、空気入ってないからね。エナドリ漬け。
Ah, true, since there's no air. Energy drink-marinated.
エナドリ漬けになってるね。そう、だから、えっとね、
Marinated in energy drinks. That's right, so, um,
そうそして、シリアルナンバーが入っていまーす！いーいですね！かわいいかわいい！
And so, a serial number is included! That's nice! Cute, cute!
そして、裏面は、りぃち先生が描いてくれたイラストにねねからのメッセージがついてきまーす！いいね！
And the back features an illustration drawn by Riiichi-sensei, with a message from Nene! Nice!
そして、次ー！ねっこタンブラー！かわいい！ちょっと大人っぽい感じの！
And next! The Neko Tumbler! Cute! With a slightly mature vibe!
余白がなかったんだよね、元々ね。今回は余白を活かした感じにして。かわいい。
There wasn't much margin originally. This time we made it so the margin is utilized. Cute.
あの、みんながね、あのコミュニティでよく飲んでるあのコーヒーのカップあるじゃん？あれがスポットそのまま入るサイズ！いい！便利！
That coffee cup everyone often drinks in the community, right? It's a size that fits right in! Good! Handy!
そう、なので、おしゃれ隠れねっこグッズとして使ってください。絶対重宝しいわ。
So please use it as a stylish, hidden Neko merch item. It'll definitely come in handy.
そして次！ねっこぬいぐるみカレンダー！
And next! The Neko Plush Calendar!
かわいい！これはね、マジでいつになっても使えるカレンダーですね。
Cute! This is a calendar you can truly use no matter what year it is.
そして、真ん中の鏡みたいになっているところが、ブロマイド、あ、じゃなくて、えっと、チェキ風のブロマイドの、あれがぴったり中に入るようになっておりまーす！いいじゃーん！
And the mirror-like part in the middle is made so that abromide, oh wait, a cheki-style bromide fits right inside! How nice!
お気に入りのね、ホロメンとか、ねねのブロマイドのカードを入れてください！入れてください！入れてください！
Please insert your favorite Holomen or Nene's bromide card! Please insert it!
そして、上のねねの部分なんだけど、これなと取り外しができます！ぬいぐるみの部分！そう、ねねのぬいぐるみとして使えるので、みんなどっかにキーホルダーとして飾ったりとか、そういうこともできちゃいまーす！いいですねー！かわいい！
And the Nene part on top, you can detach this! The plush part! Yes, since it can be used as a Nene plush, everyone can hang it somewhere as a keychain or display it like that! That's great! Cute!
スポット取れてね、あの、磁石になってるんだっけかな？なんか、ぴたっとどっかにくっつけることができるの！冷蔵庫とかね！
It comes off easily, and it's magnetic, right? You can stick it right onto something like a fridge!
だから、いろんなところにねねこと一緒にねねを旅に連れて行ってください！かわいい！
So take Nene along on your travels with Nekoko to all sorts of places! Cute!
そして、どん！ボイス！ボイスもねねのボイスも出まーす！
And boom! Voice! Nene's voice is also coming out!
どんなボイスなんだい？「きみと二人で誕生日パーティ！」
What kind of voice is it? 'Birthday party just for the two of us!'
二人で歌いたんですよ、ねねを！私たちもそこに入って
We wanted to sing it together, Nene! We entered there too—
ねぽらぼどうすんだよ！ねぽらぼそこ置け！
What about Nelabo?! Put Nelabo down over there!
ていうかこんなね、あさびたびたでね、紹介するもんじゃないんだけど
I mean, it's not like you should introduce it while being all slobbery like this,
ねねとねっこをふったりきりのね、ラブラブいちゃいちゃバースデーボイスが出まーす！ね、誕生日だしな、紹介してください。
A super lovey-dovey birthday voice of just Nene and Neko comes out! Well, it's her birthday, so please introduce it.
そして、フルセットがこちら！キャンバスアート、ねっこ証明書、タンブラー、カレンダー、ボイス、そしてチェキ風ブロマイドカード！
And the full set is right here! Canvas art, Neko certificate, tumbler, calendar, voice, and cheki-style bromide card!
ぴったり入ります、ねねのカレンダーのの中。入れなきゃね、これ。そう！
It fits right inside Nene's calendar. We've gotta put it in. Yes!
そして今回は、えっと、ちょっと、申し訳ないのですが数量限定バージョンがあります！
And this time, um, apologies, but there is a limited quantity version!
数量限定バージョン買っていただくと、ねねの直筆サイン＋メッセージ入りのブロマイド風、え、チェキカードが来ます！
If you buy the limited quantity version, a cheki-style card featuring Nene's handwritten autograph plus a message comes with it!
そしてフルセットには、箔押しサイン、複製サイン付きのもの付きます！
And the full set comes with items featuring foil-stamped and duplicated signatures!
そしてフルセットをご購入してくれたみなさんには、こちら、ねねの大本なしフリートークボイス！なんですかこれ！聞いたことない、聞いたことない！大本なし？聞いたことない！
And to everyone who purchases the full set, here is Nene's unscripted free talk voice! What is this?! I've never heard of it! Unscripted? Never heard of it!
そのねねが練習とかね、大詰めのになっているときに、みんなへのね、頑張りたいていう思いを込めたボイスをここにぎゅっと収めました！
When Nene was practicing and in the final stretch, she packed her feelings of wanting to do her best for everyone right into this voice!
なるほど、じゃあ、本音、本音のボイスってことね？そう、ねねの本音ボイス！
I see, so it's her true feelings voice? That's right, Nene's true feelings voice!
そして最近話題のこちらです！
And this has been a hot topic lately!
わあ！
Wow!
ホルカガ、ホルカガついてきまーす！
Oh, Holoca is included with every purchase!
ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲーム、ねねのお誕生日バージョンが！
The hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME Nene Birthday version!
これめちゃくちゃ可愛い！
This is so cute!
かわいいですね。なんかちょっとエモい雰囲気もあって、いいなって思います。
It's so cute with a slightly emotional vibe.
そして今回なんですけれども、ちょっと色々、あのトラブルがありまして、カートオープンがですね、21時15分になっております！
Also, due to some trouble, the cart opens at 9:15 PM!
まだ！
Not yet!
もうちょっと時間がある、もうちょっと時間がある。
There's still a little more time.
だからね、ちょっと最後までね、の放送を見て、そのあとあの、よければチェックしていただければと思います。
So please watch until the end and check it out!
セットよろしくお願いします！お願いします！
Please check out the set! Thank you!
今ね、コメントにもあの、貼って、固定してもらうので、よかったらそちらからチェックしてください！21時15分！
It's pinned in the chat, so please check it there! 9:15 PM!
はい。というわけで、ねね、最後の曲がありますので、
Yes. With that, we have our final song,
ブルグラもやる？ブルグラもやろうぜ！めんげいじやろうぜ！
Let's do this and that too!
数くわと持ったら…
If you thought it was Kazukuwa—
ありがとう！ストレス発散！
Thank you for the stress relief!
2人にはこのあとのメンゲン放送にも出てきてもらいます！ありがとう！
The two of them will join the membership stream too!
というわけで、最後の曲、行ってみましょうか！どん！
And with that, let's go to our final song! Boom!
次は、あれ？この曲はなんだろう？
Next is... huh? What song is this?
わあ、もしかして、この曲は……！
Wow, could this song be...?!
よーし、この曲、行ってみちゃおう！みんな楽しみにしててねーん！
All right, let's go with this one! Look forward to it!
最後の、最後の曲はですね、LOVE受信ヒクツ発信でいきたいと思います！
Our final song is "LOVE Jushin Hikutsu Hasshin"!
イェーイ！こちらね、お誕生日当日に出た新曲になります！MVもね、もう公開されているので、よければチェックお願いします！
It's a new song released on my birthday! Please check the MV!
そして最後、まだね、あの、さっきアンケートで選ばれなかった新衣装たちがありますので、そちらに着替えて最後の曲を歌っていきたいと思います！
And I'll change into the other new outfit for the final song!
どの衣装にしようかな？どっちにしようかな？ヨセ衣装で、決定！
Which outfit? The Yose outfit, decided!
時間間に合いマジック！はっ！
Just in time magic! Ha!
それでは聞いてください。LOVE受信ヒクツ発信！
Now then, please listen to "LOVE Jushin Hikutsu Hasshin"!
(すきすきすきにさせてみせるから)
Because I'll make you love, love, love me!
こっちを向いて、ばかぁ
Look this way, you idiot!
ワクワクでいっぱいの日にしていくから
I'll make this day full of excitement!
ねねピーむで、ぱぁきゅーん！
Nene-Pimu, par-pyun!
画面前でのおめかし準備
Preparing to dress up in front of the screen
今日は何する？アイデア募集
What shall we do today? Taking ideas!
そだエゴサで、こっそり君に聴いてみちゃおう、教えてくれる？
So I'll secretly ask you through a search, will you tell me?
「ねねちだけが、一生推しだよ！」
"Nenechi is my one and only oshi for life!"
嬉しくってハッピネス
So happy, pure happiness!
でも、待って……
But wait...
5時間前の「最推しらぶじゅりゅうご」
Five hours ago: "My ultimate oshi, love juryuugo"
ふざけんなよ早く消せよ
Are you kidding me? Hurry up and delete it!
えへっ悪いよね、秘密を持ったアイドル
That's bad, right? An idol with secrets.
信じてるこれからも、君との未来進もう……っ！
I believe in our future together, let's move forward...!
来てくれたの励みになるよ
It encourages me when you come!
一生懸命伝え るねっ
I'll do my best to convey it!
「ねねち推しです！」ありがとうだけど
"I'm a Nenechi oshi!" Thank you, but...
それ別口のこの推しマークじゃね？
Isn't that someone else's oshi mark?
DD歓迎♡そんなの嫌い
DDs are welcome? I hate that!
追いかける浮気はちねっ！
Chasing around and cheating is the worst!
響く…
It echoes...
ハッピーギラファ～～～！！
Happy Giraffa~~~!!
ねねちのギラギラファンミーティングへようこそ！！
Welcome to Nenechi's Giragira Fan Meeting!!
さあ！ツノと頬をなでーーーく伸ばして
Come on! Stretch your horns and cheeks far out--
おもいっぴり、楽しんじゃおうね！
And let's enjoy it to the fullest!
それじゃあ、いっくよーーーっ！
Here we go~~~!
アミーを！カケロロ！
Cast amii! Kakero!
ビバ！ギラファ！（uh！！）
Viva! Giraffa! (uh!!)
ギラギラ最高だね kabu-kuwa
Giragira is the best, kabu-kuwa
クリクリおめめラブ kabu-kuwa
Big round eyes, love, kabu-kuwa
愛の（ふーーっ！）ダンスはムチョムチョ
The dance of love (fu~~!) is so very passionate
飛んで（ふーーっ！）シュビドゥバメロメロ
Flying (fu~~!) shubiduba, completely melting
（あわわわわーーっ！）
(Awawawawa~~!)
みんな（ふーーっ！）集まれゾロゾロ
Everyone (fu~~!) gathering in droves
こん^^ちゅ☆ちゅ☆
Kon^^ chu☆ chu☆
パヤパヤパヤパ
Paya paya paya pa
他の子にも言ってたらマジで
If you say that to other girls, seriously
ショッケイネネネネ
Shokkei Nene Nene
ネネだけだよね？
It's only Nene, right?
ネネだけだよねぇ…？
It's only Nene, right...?
金髪ってだけで
Just because I'm blonde
陽キャだと思うなよ！
Don't assume I'm an extrovert!
引きこもるぞ、泣いて
I'll shut myself away, crying
まんぞく（えへっ！）
Fully satisfied (eheh!)
ひくつもの光まとったアイドル
An idol wrapped in the light of a shut-in
信じてるこれからも君といること
Believing that I'll be with you from now on
……「はい」は？？？？☆
......Where is your "Yes"????☆
（すきすきすきにさせてみせるから）
(Because I'll make you love, love, love me)
こっちを向けてえらい！
Good job for turning this way!
（むくむくでいっぱいの日にしてくから）
(Because I'll make it a day full of bugs)
ねねちむでばきゅーーーんっ！
Nenechimu baquuuun!
ばきゅーーーんっ！
Baquuuun!
このあと21時15分から
After this, starting at 21:15
兎田ぺこらそしてみこもよろしくねー！
Usada Pekora and Miko, please treat them well too!
ハッピーギラファ～！ねねちのギラギラファンミーティングへようこそ！
Happy Giraffa~! Welcome to Nenechi's Giragira Fan Meeting!
今回はゲストの皆といっしょにギラギラしていきたいと思います、それではいくよー！
This time, we're going to get all sparkly and wild together with our guests! Here we go!
【ゲスト】兎田ぺこら
[Guest: Usada Pekora]
夏色まつり
Natsuiro Matsuri
赤井はあと
Akai Haato
さくらみこ
Sakura Miko
アキ・ローゼンタール
Aki Rosenthal
宝鐘マリン
Houshou Marine
雪花ラミィ
Yukihana Lamy
獅白ぼたん
Shishiro Botan
ねねちのギラギラファンミーティング 作詞・作曲・編曲：まろん (IOSYS)
Nenechi's Giragira Fan Meeting - Lyrics, Music & Arrangement: Maron (IOSYS)
【オケ制作】HighkaraSound
[Playback Production: HighkaraSound]
【演出映像制作】chaosgroove
[Stage Visual Production: chaosgroove]
【楽曲選択映像】Itsuki Harada (NENTEN), さこくちゃん (NENTEN)
[Song Selection Visuals: Itsuki Harada (NENTEN), Sakoku-chan (NENTEN)]
【振付】まいどん (あでんガールズ), ARAKIYUKA inc., MAI ITAMOTO, MIKA
[Choreography: Maidon (Aden Girls), ARAKIYUKA inc., MAI ITAMOTO, MIKA]
【サムネイルイラスト】こゆびたべる
[Thumbnail Illustration: Koyubi Taberu]
【ロゴ・サムネイルデザイン】ミナトデザイン
[Logo & Thumbnail Design: Minato Design]
【SpecialThanks】小林紗彩他
[Special Thanks: Saaya Kobayashi & others]
ねねねねねねねね！
Nenenenenenenene!
強くてかっこいいキラキラ輝くわ
Strong and cool, sparkling and shining!
宝物だね イッパツキラキラ
It's a treasure, a flash of sparkle!
家族は最高！イエイ！家族はイエイ！
Family is the best! Yeah! Family is yeah!
家族は最高！イエイ！家族は最高！
Family is the best! Yeah! Family is the best!
家族はイエイ！家族はイエイ！
Family is yeah! Family is yeah!
家族はクネクネ おもしろラブ家族はイエイ！
Family is quirky, a funny, loving family, yeah!
家族はイエイ！家族はイエイ！
Family is yeah! Family is yeah!
本気ゅ！きゅ！パヤパヤパヤパ！
Seriously! Pyaya pyaya pyaya pa!
パヤパヤパヤパ！
Pyaya pyaya pyaya pa!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ねねリズム バースデーライブ！
[Nene Rhythm Birthday Live!]